# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, I am Chef Wang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
For today’s video, I’m going to share with you a homestyle dish
# 豆腐煎肉末
Fried stuffed tofu
# 首先我们准备瘦肉2小块
First, prepare two pieces of lean meat
# 切成小片之后剁碎备用
Slice then mince them
# 同学们最好选择略带肥油的瘦肉
It’s better to choose lean meat with a tad fat on it
# 这样口感和香味更佳
The texture and the flavor are better
# 肉末剁好之后放入碗中下一步开始调味
Put the minced meat in a bowl, and start seasoning
# 准备生姜1小块剁碎备用
Mince a small piece of ginger
# 准备适量的小葱头剁碎备用
Finely dice some shallot
# 碗中加入食用盐1克
Add 1g salt in the bowl
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Add some white pepper powder
# 加入生抽酱油2克
Add 2g light soy sauce
# 然后搅拌至粘稠上劲即可
Mix well until tacky
# 下一步开始准备处理豆腐
Next step, prepare the tofu
# 准备豆腐1小块切成薄片备用
Prepare the tofu into thin slices
# 同学们最好选择老豆腐
Firm tofu is the best choice
# 这样切的时候才不容易碎
It doesn't crumble as easily when sliced
# 豆腐切好之后再加入适量的肉末夹在中间
Spread some meat filling in between tofu slices
# 夹好肉末之后在整个豆腐周围涂抹上干淀粉
Cover the tofu in dry starch once stuffed
# 这一步的目的是防止豆腐下锅煎的时候散开
This step is to prevent tofu from breaking apart while frying
# 最后再撒上剩余的淀粉
Last, spread the remaining starch
# 下一步开始调料汁
Next step, prepare the sauce
# 碗中加入食用盐1克
Add one gram of salt in the bowl
# 加入生抽酱油3克
Add three grams of light soy sauce
# 加入蚝油3克
Add three grams of oyster sauce
# 加入老抽2克
Add two grams of dark soy sauce
# 调好味之后搅拌均匀
Mix well after seasoning
# 中途再加入适量的干淀粉拌匀
Add some dry starch, continue mixing
# 最后准备鸡蛋几个搅散备用
Last, whip a few eggs
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
Use some oil to rinse the wok
# 同学们这一步不能马虎否则豆腐下锅必粘
DO NOT skip this step, or the tofu will stick to the wok
# 热油倒出之后再加入少许的底油
Remove the hot oil, then add some base oil
# 下一步开始煎豆腐
Next step, fry the tofu
# 首先我们将豆腐均匀地裹上鸡蛋液
First, dip the tofu in egg wash and coat evenly
# 这一步的目的是让豆腐与豆腐之间连接得更紧密
This helps tofu slices stick better
# 豆腐摆好形状之后调微小火煎制10分钟
After placing the tofu, change to low heat and fry for 10 minutes
# 同学们这一步必须微小火慢煎
It must be fried with a low heat
# 否则豆腐中间的肉不熟
Or the meat filling between the tofu won’t cook through
# 煎制8分钟之后将剩余的蛋液下锅
After 8 minutes, add the remaining egg
# 然后继续转微小火煎至定型
Then keep frying over low heat until the shape sets
# 煎制10分钟之后反过来再继续煎4分钟
After 10 minutes, flip over and fry for another 4 minutes
# 煎制4分钟之后将豆腐饼倒出备用
Take the tofu "omelette" out after 4 minutes
# 然后我们在锅中加入事先调好的料汁开中小火烧开
Then, pour the prepared sauce into the wok and bring to a boil over medium low heat
# 当汁水浓稠之后先盛出一半
After the sauce has thickened, scoop out half of it
# 然后将豆腐下锅均匀地粘上汤汁即可
Put the tofu back to the wok, and pour the sauce on top evenly
# 最后撒上适量的葱花即可上菜
Lastly, garnish with some chopped green onion
# 一道非常美味的豆腐煎肉末就制作完成
A very delicious fried stuffed tofu is done
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，最好选择紧实一些的老豆腐，这样不容易碎
# 第二，料汁可以适量的多一些，在出菜的时候才能均匀的挂上汤汁以保证足味
# 第三，煎豆腐必须小火煎够14分钟，否则中间的肉末不熟
# 豆腐煎鸡蛋的技术总结完毕
Technical summary
Firstly, it’s better to use firm tofu as it doesn't crumble as much
Secondly, make sure you prepare enough sauce to coat the tofu evenly to ensure the flavor
Thirdly, the tofu has to be fried over low heat for at least 14 minutes, otherwise, the meat filling in between might not be fully cooked
That’s all for the technical summary of “fried stuffed tofu”